

## **Contacts**

olena.pobehailo@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u>

**GitHub** 

<u>Telegram</u>

Lviv, Ukraine

## **Portfolio link**

## **Tech skills**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Saas
- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- REST API
- TypeScript

# Soft skills

- Strong analytical thinking
- Willingness to learn
- Attentive to details and precise
- Solution-focused thinking
- Calm and determined

# Languages

English - intermediate Ukrainian - native

# Olena Pobehailo

Junior Full Stack developer

Having worked for many years as a lead engineer specializing in metal science, I've become proficient in solving various tasks quickly and efficiently, analyzing large amounts of information, paying close attention to detail, working effectively in a team, maintaining composure under time constraints, and always seeking new knowledge.

Currently, I am a motivated Full Stack developer, that is committed to lifelong learning. I have a strong background in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js

### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

### **Contacts REST API**

API for managing contacts. It includes endpoints for CRUD operations, user authentication, user registration, login, logout, and avatar management.

Tech: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

Code, Live page

### LearnLingo

An app for an online language teaching company. Users filter teachers by language, level, rates, and add favorites. Firebase handles auth.

Tech: React, Firebase, Styled components

Code, Live page

## **Movie Search App**

The TMDB Movie Search App is a web tool using the TMDB API, enabling users to find information about movies, actors, and reviews on The Movie Database platform.

Tech: JavaScript, React, Redux, Styled components

Code, Live page

### Pixabay Image Search App

The Pixabay Image Search App is an application that searches for images. Users enter a search query, and the app displays relevant images.

Tech: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS

Code, Live page

#### Cucina di Catherina

A responsively designed e-commerce website. We at GoIT built this project in collaboration with six other students. I successfully created a modal window.

**Tech:** HTML, SASS, Responsive/Adaptive design, BEM methodology, JavaScript Code, Live page

#### WebStudio

The project implemented responsive/adoptive design for the best possible website viewing experience using HTML and SASS.

Tech: HTML, SASS, Responsive/Adaptive design, BEM methodology.

Code, Live page

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Lead engineer, engineer of metallographic laboratory

Azovstal Iron and Steel Works, Mariupol (2013-2022)

Conducted comprehensive metallographic investigations to:

- Determine the root causes of component failures.
- Identify the underlying reasons for defects.
- Evaluate and determine the optimal variant of technology.

Achievement: Conducted metallographic research resulted in the implementation of technologies that reduced defects and downtime, improved efficiency, and ensured high product quality.

### **Engineer of heat treatment laboratory**

Azovstal Iron and Steel Works, Mariupol (1995-2013)

Analyzed extensive datasets to:

- Develop of processing techniques for new products.
- Adjust existing technologies for optimization.
- Modify chemical compositions to achieve specific quality standards.

Achievement: Developed technologies, optimized materials and processes, and improved product quality to meet or exceed industry standards.

#### **EDUCATION**

IT School GoIT

2022 - 2024

Fullstack Developer

#### Pre-Azov State Technical University, Mariupol

Metal Science, Technology, and Equipment for Heat Treatment of Metals